# uanzhuo Wu

August-Bebel-Str. 17a / A113, 01219 Dresden, Germany

🛘 +49 1746023602 | 🛂 wuhuanzhuo@gmail.com | 🌴 huanzhuo.github.io | 🛅 huanzhuo-wu-4574878b | 🎓 Google Scholar |

China (Native), English (Proficient), German (Conversational)



## **Profile**

I am Huanzhuo Wu, a Junior researcher at the Deutsche Telekom Chair of Communication Networks (ComNets) at Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden), Germany. My particular research interest is In-network Computing, Software Defined Networks (SDN), and Algorithm Optimization, with more than 20 peer-reviewed publications and several research projects. For more detailed and up-to-date information about my projects, publications, and activities, please kindly refer to my personal website at https://huanzhuo.github.io or by scanning the QR code in the footer.

# Work Experience

## **Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)**

Dresden, Germany

JUNIOR RESEARCHER

Feb. 2017 - Present

- · Coordinating and managing research projects, in cooperation with Ericsson, Robert Bosch GmbH, Huawei Munich Research Center, TU Munich, RWTH Aachen, and other key partners.
- Conducting research on In-network Computing and Industrial 5G, with publications, talks, and demos on e.g., IEEE GlobCom, IEEE ICC, IEEE Internet of Things Journal, CES, and Hanover Messe.
- · Applying for funding on research projects, i.e., Exist for research transfer from the Federal Ministry of Economics and Technology Germany in 2022, Software Campus for IT-Talent from the Federal Ministry of Education and Research Germany in 2020.
- · Teaching and supervising students.

**Audi China** Beijing, China Aug. 2016 - Nov. 2016 IT INTERN

• Managing and supporting projects related to digitization (Audi Connect, App Center, and Cloud Project).

• Supporting enterprise-university cooperation.

**BMW AG** Dingolfing, Germany

QUALITY MANAGEMENT INTERN

- May. 2015 Oct. 2015
- Optimizing and updating the quality management metamodel.
- Creating quality reports.

## **Education**

#### Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• Topic: In-network Audio Processing for Low-latency Industrial Applications.

• Quality management by supporting SAP solutions in the production plant.

• Grad Year: Expected Q3 2022.

## Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTE SCIENCE

• Master Thesis: Regenerating Codes.

• Thesis Grade: 1.3.

**TUDIAS** Dresden, Germany

GERMAN LANGUAGE COURSE

Aug. 2011 - Mar. 2012 • Final Grade: DSH 2

**Chang'an University** 

Xi'an, China

Dresden, Germany Feb. 2017 - Present

Dresden, Germany

Apr. 2012 - Dec. 2016

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTE ENGINEERING

Bachelor Thesis: Wireless Sensor Network.

· Final Grade: A.

Sept. 2007 - July. 2011



# **Project Experience**

**6G-life** funded by BMBF

WITH TECHNISCHE UNIVERSITÄT MÜNCHEN (TU MUNICH)

May. 2022 - Present

- Contributing to the topic on accelerating controlling systems with In-network Computing.
- Coordinating research agenda with partners, including research topics and publication plans.

Hexa-X funded by European Commission

WITH NOKIA, ERICSSON, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

June. 2021 - Present

- Contributing to the topic on integrating AI into networks.
- Presenting project results on international events, e.g., conferences and exhibitions.

## **Software Campus Net-BliSS**

funded by BMBF

WITH HUAWEI MUNICH RESEARCH CENTER

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Leading the project on In-network Computing for time-sensitive industrial applications.
- · Creating project proposal, including research subjects, work plan, manpower, and budget plan.
- Coordinating with the industrial partner.
- · Managing research progress, research/student assistant, outcome presentation on international events.
- Communicating and reporting to Projektträger.
- · Training in leadership and management.

**5Gang** funded by BMBF

WITH ERICSSON, ROBERT BOSCH GMBH, RWTH AACHEN, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

- Responsible for the project on utilizing 5G in the industry.
- · Collaborating with the industrial partners.
- Presenting project results on international events, e.g., conferences and exhibitions.
- · Managing research progress, research/student assistant.
- · Communicating and reporting to Projektträger.
- · Organizing and participating in workshops.

FastRobotics funded by BMBF

WITH KUKA, FRAUNHOFER IFF, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

VITH NUKA, FRAUNHOFER IFF, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

• Contributing to the topic on Digital Twins.

Mar. 2017 - Dec.2020

Mar. 2017 - Nov.2020

# **Selected Publications**

The complete publication list is available on my personal website at https://huanzhuo.github.io or via the QR code in the footer.

#### **Journal Articles**

- Huanzhuo Wu and Yunbin Shen and Xun Xiao and Giang T. Nguyen and Artur Hecker and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Accelerating Industrial IoT Acoustic Data Separation with In-Network Computing", In IEEE Internet of Things Journal, pp. 1-15, 2022.
- Jia He and **Huanzhuo Wu** and Xun Xiao and Riccardo Bassoli and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Functional Split of In-Network Deep Learning for 6G: A Feasibility Study", In IEEE Wireless Communications, pp. 1-7, (submitted, 2022).
- Huanzhuo Wu and Zuo Xiang and Giang T. Nguyen and Yunbin Shen and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Computing Meets Network: COIN-aware Offloading for Data-intensive Blind Source Separation", In IEEE Network Magazine, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and Giang T. Nguyen and Anil K. Chorppath and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Network Slicing for Conditional Monitoring in the Industrial Internet of Things", Online IEEE Software Defined Networks, IEEE Softwarization, Jan. 2018.

#### **Conference Papers**

- **Huanzhuo Wu** and Jia He and Máté Tömösközi and Zuo Xiang and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "In-Network Processing for Low-Latency Industrial Anomaly Detection in Softwarized Networks", In 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference: Next-Generation Networking and Internet (Globecom2021 NGNI), Madrid, Spain, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and Yunbin Shen and Xun Xiao and Artur Hecker and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "In-Network Processing Acoustic Data for Anomaly Detection in Smart Factory", In 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference: IoT and Sensor Networks (Globecom2021 IoTSN), Madrid, Spain, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and Jia He and Máté Tömösközi and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Abstraction-based Multi-object Acoustic Anomaly Detection for Low-complexity Big Data Analysis", In WS17 IEEE ICC 2021 Workshop on Communication, Computing, and Networking in Cyber-Physical Systems (WS17 ICC'21 Workshop CCN-CPS), Montreal, Canada, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and levgenii A. Tsokalo and David Kußand Hani Salah and Lukas Pingel and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Demonstration of Network Slicing for Flexible Conditional Monitoring in Industrial IoT Networks", In 2019 16th IEEE Annual Consumer Communications & Networking Conference (CCNC) (CCNC 2019), Las Vegas, USA, 2019.

## **Book Chapter**

• Fabrizio Granelli and Giang T. Nguyen and **Huanzhuo Wu**, "Realizing Network Slicing", In Computing in Communication Networks –From Theory to Practice, Elsevier, vol. 1, pp. 271-289, 2020.

